MUHAMMAD ABUSAA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

+10 years experience of software development . Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Skilled leader who has the proven ability to motivate, educate, and manage a team of professionals to build software programs and effectively track changes. Confident communicator and strategic thinker

WORK HISTORY



TECH TEAM LEAD, THIQAH BUSINESS SERVICES

1/9/2019 - Present



PRODUCT MANAGER / TEAM LEAD, NETWAYS, RIYADH

1/1/2018 - 1/8/2019



TECHNICAL TEAM LEADER, NETWAYS, RIYADH

1/1/2017 - 30/12/2017



SENIOR SOLUTION DESIGNER, NETWAYS, RIYADH

1/12/2012 - 1/1/2017



SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OGER SYSTEMS, RIYADH

• 1/1/2010 – 30/11/2012

SKILLS

- Team management / leadership
- Containerization and Docker
- Container orchestration / Kubernetes

- Azure DevOps.
- Product owner / scrum master / solution management
- Business analysis
- .Net Core / Framework , Web API
- Client Side Development
- SharePoint Understanding
- Office 365 Understanding
- CRM Understanding
- BizTalk Understanding
- K2 Understanding
- Angular JS SPA
- Project Scoping
- Application design
- Preparing demos and related presentation

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

INTERNET AND ESERVICES PROJECTS

- Ministry of commerce / Franchise : .net Core / Angular
- Ministry of commerce / Maroof : .net Core / containers and Kubernetes .
- SFDA eservices project : .Net Core , Kubernetes , React
- Ministry of interior Mifon Project : Angular JS , Web Api , SharePoint , CRM
- GMCO internet website : SharePoint 2013 , Word Automation
- The centennial fund eServices website (eServices using .Net)
- Alrajhi Takaful Internet website (eServices using .Net)
- Council of Saudi Chambers Internet website : SharePoint 2010
- High Commission for the Development of Arriyadh website: SharePoint 2010

ERP

• RDCCI ERP web application (using asp.net web forms)

Page | 2 Muhammad Abusaa

INTRANET PROJECTS

Sanabil Intranet : SharePoint 2016 / CMS

• SASO Intranet: SharePoint 2010 / .Net / AngularJs / K2

• Ecra intranet: SharePoint 2013 / Word Automation

GMCO intranet: SharePoint 2013 / CMS

 COE enterprise content management system : SharePoint 2013

• AlSubaie intranet : SharePoint 2010

Riyadh Chamber of Commerce Intranet : SharePoint 2010

EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF JORDAN, AMMAN

2005-2009

CERTIFICATIONS

Administering Visual Studio Team Foundation Server

Managing Office 365 Identities and Requirements

Developing Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013 Advanced Solutions

Developing Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013 Core Solutions

Advanced Solutions of Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013











Page | 3 Muhammad Abusaa